

Applicant for:

# Senior Java Engineer ~2,000\$ (SL: 05)

Dr.JOY 11 January 2021

# **Pham Hong Son**

★ hongson890@gmail.com

Main interests: AngularJS, JavaScript

What skills, work projects or achievements make you a strong candidate for this position?

Dear HR Team,

I am writing to apply for Java position in your company as advertised recently, Please find attached to this email a copy of my updated CV that details my past experience and projects,

Best regards,

Son Pham.

#### **Son Pham**

## Senior Full-Stack Developer

Hanoi, Vietnam (GMT +7) • (84) 902 264213

hongson890@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/son-pham-46733337

#### **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

10 years of experiences in software development for many different domains, such as Online Payment, Forex, Supply Chain, etc. Have 3 years working remotely with clients in United Kingdom, Estonia and Korea. The goal is seeking a position of IT Leader to put the experiences into use to help the business meet strategic and operational goals by identifying opportunities to deploy new technology and ensure operational efficiency.

#### HARD SKILLS

- Backend Languages: Java (10 years), Nodejs (3 years)
- Frontend Techniques: AngularJS/TypeScript (5 years), ReactJS (3 years), VueJS (2 year), JQuery (5 years), HTML and CSS (10 years), Plain Javascript (10 years)
- **Java Framework:** Struts 2 (5 years), Spring (7 years), Hibernate (10 years)
- Message Queue: RabbitMO
- NodeJS Framework: Express (3 years)
- **Testing Framework:** Cucumber (5 years), Junit (10 years), Jasmine (3 years)
- Databases: MS SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle, Postgres, MongoDB, SQLite, Neo4J
- Cache Engine: Memcache, Redis, Browser cache, Database Caching
- Web Service: Rest API (10 years), SOAP, WebSocket
- **Search Engine:** Elastic Search
- **Source Control:** GIT (Bitbucket, Github, Gitlab), SVN (Tortoise SVN)
- OS: Ubuntu, Debian, CentOS, Redhat (RHEL), MacOS, Windows
- Cloud service: AWS, Google Cloud Services, Vult
- **CI/CD**: Gitlab Pipeline, Bitbucket Pipeline, Jenkins, Docker.
- **Task management tools:** Jira, Redmine, Trello
- Analysis & Design Tools: Microsoft Visio, Draw.io, Xmind
- Design and Modeling: UML Diagrams (behavioral diagrams, structure diagrams)
- **IDEs & Programming tools:** Eclipse, MS Visual Studio, IntelliJ IDEA
- Container Orchestration Engine: Kubernetes, Docker Swarm
- **Design Patterns:** Creational Pattern (Singleton, Factory, Prototype), Structural Design Pattern (Façade, Bridge), Behavioral Design Patterns (Observer), Other Patterns (DAO, Dependency Injection, MVC).

### **SOFT SKILLS**

- Remote Technical Proficiency: Proficient in using all popular remote working tools: MS Office, Google Drive, Dropbox, Zoom, Telegram, WhatsApp, Skype, Slack, Trello, Cisco Webex Meetings, Microsoft Teams, Jira, Confluences.
- Communication skills: Excellent communication skills in English writing skill (advanced) verbal skills (intermediate).
- Teamwork (advance), problem solving: (good), critical thinking (good), time management (advance)

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Freelancer

Senior Remote Full Stack Developer

08/2018-Present

# sedex.com - Ethical Data Platform (Bailey, London, UK)

A membership organization that provides one of the world's leading online platforms for companies to manage and improve working conditions in global supply.

# Responsibility:

- Work with development teams and product managers to ideate software solutions and deliver new features
- Design client-side and server-side architecture
- Testing and fixing bugs or other coding issues
- Write technical documentations on Confluences (UML diagrams, design solution)

Technologies: Micro-services, Angular JS, Angular 8, Java 8, Spring, Ionic, Electron, PostgreSQL, NEO4J, Cucumber, Grunt, Bitbucket, Jenkins, Marathon, Docker, Kubernetes.

### continuity.cash - An intuitive and cross-platform finance app (Tallinn, Estonia)

A smart, easy-to-use app that allows users to track and categorize in-and-out money Responsibility:

- Developing front end and backend application architecture.
- Designing and developing APIs.
- Setting up tools and required infrastructure.
- Selecting and deploying appropriate CI/CD tools

Technologies: Java 8, Spring Boot, Postgres SQL, Keycloak, Angular 8, PWA, Gitlab, Jenkin, Docker

# MMS project in twendeesoft.com- Outsourcing Company (Hanoi, Vietnam)

An internal system administrator to install, locate, maintain and monitor hardware and software status for many big organizations.

### Responsibility:

- Developing user-facing applications using Vue.js
- Building modular and reusable components and libraries
- Designing and developing APIs using Java Spring
- Working with Product Owner and BA to finalize design solution

Technologies: Java 8, Spring Boot, MySQL, Vue JS

## Net Company, Hanoi Vietnam

Senior Full Stack Developer

08/2017-07/2018

#### optunli.com – Online Recruitment Platform

An online recruitment platform that will enable HR and businesses to take advantage of trends in the workplace such as flexibility and the gig economies, well-being and career experiences, improving engagement and productivity.

# Responsibility:

- Develop websites and solutions using HTML, CSS, Angular 8, Nodejs
- Participate in code reviews, stand-ups, and team-building exercises

Technologies: Express, MongoDB, Redis, Elastic Search, Angular 8, Redux

### Elcom JSC, Hanoi Vietnam

Java Developer, Technical Leader, Project Manager

10/2013-07/2017

### **Project X – Security Alert System for Vietnam Ministry of Defense**

Safety warning system for the entire defense network, software and hardware system administrator Responsibility:

- Assembling and leading the project team
- Ensuring the project stays on schedule and adheres to the deadlines
- Discussing potential projects and their parameters with clients, executives, and software developers
- Delivering completed software products to clients and performing regular checks on the products' performance

Technologies: Java, Struts2, Hibernate, Oracle, IBM Siem, Hp Arcsight, D3js, Websocket, Bootstrap

#### Nextop Co LTD, Hanoi Vietnam

Java Full Stack Developer

02/2013-09/2013

### Building Forex System for Nature Forex Ltd, DMM FX Australia Pty Ltd

An international broker which provides financial and investment services worldwide. Our company specializes in FX, Metals, Indices, Oil, Social Trading and Binary Options.

# Responsibilities:

- Designing, implementing, and maintaining Java applications that are often high-volume and lowlatency, required for mission-critical systems
- Managing Java and Java EE application development
- Conducting software analysis, programming, testing, and debugging
- Writing well-designed, efficient, and testable code

Technology: Struts 2, Hibernate, Spring MVC, MySQL, WebSocket, RabbitMQ

#### RED ARROW JSC, Hanoi Vietnam

Junior Java Developer

05/2011-01/2013

#### **Mobile Charging Top-up System**

The online payment system allows users to top-up their phones or buy cards Responsibilities:

- Identify and analyze user requirements.
- Plan and execute all deployment of system features and monitor for successful integration, maintaining the system throughout its lifecycle
- Developed and tested system ensures accuracy for users
- Security settings and system backup ensure 24/7 online system
- Document system design, operating documentation

Technology: .NET, Java, Oracle, My SQL, SQL Server, Hibernate, SOAP API

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Software Engineering, Feb 2012 Hanoi, Vietnam

Honor Computer Science Program – Posts and Telecommunications Institute of Technology

Further information is ready to be supplied as requested

Thanks for your kind attention given to my CV